A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 1-3254 FA739A
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Visit to Washington University, St. Louis, Missouri, May 18-19 (Reports 001925), 1967; Morrill, J. L. (James Lewis), 1891-1979 (Box 74)
  Memo to Harry Wilhelm of the Ford Foundation. Evaluation of the university's Latin American Studies Program.
  International Division Latin America and the Caribbean;International Division/Office of the Vice President
  06790023;06300409
  Curriculum evaluation -- Missouri; Faculty evaluation -- Missouri; College teachers -- Missouri; Washington University (Saint Louis, Mo.)
- Visits to Bogota and Panama (Reports 001926), 1967; Queenan, Bernard P. (Box 74)
  Report on visits which were to renew existing contracts with organizations and individuals engaged in ETV work and to review developments.
  Television in education -- Colombia; Television in education -- Panama
- Visit to Mexico, 21 May to 11 June 1967 (Reports 001927), Queenan, Bernard P. (Box 74)
  Purpose of visit was to examine and report on activities in the general field of educational television and to make a specific study of the closed circuit projects in the Instituto Tecnologico y de Estudios Superiores de Monterrey, Nuevo Leon.
  Television in education -- Mexico
- Visit to Lima (Reports 001928), 1967; Queenan, Bernard P. (Box 74)
  Report on visit to examine the state of educational television in Peru.
  Television in education -- Peru
- The Masters' Program in the Facultad de Comercio y Administracion, Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Mexico (Reports 001929), 1968; Gibson, Cyrus F. (Box 74)
  The Master of Business Administration Program at UNAM is evaluated.
  Industrial management -- Mexico; Curriculum evaluation -- Mexico; Universities and colleges -- Graduate work -- Mexico; College teachers -- Mexico; Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México
- University of Antioquia (Reports 001930), 1965; Zisman, Samuel B. (Box 74)
  The plan for the new campus of the university is discussed.
  Architectural design -- Colombia; Campus planning -- Colombia; College buildings -- Colombia; School facilities -- Colombia; Universidad de Antioquia
- Evaluation of and recommendations for the Faculty of Engineering at the Catholic University of Peru, Lima, Peru (Reports 001931), 1966; Guralnick, Sidney A. (Box 74)
  Civil engineering -- Peru; Curriculum evaluation -- Peru; Laboratories -- Peru; Laboratories -- Furniture, equipment, etc; Engineering -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Peru; Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú
- The evolution of development strategy in Kenya (Reports 001932), 1977; Edwards, Edgar O. (Box 74)
  07790805
  Support for research and writing development policy in Kenya.
  49 leaves: ill. -- 28 cm.
  Economic development -- Kenya
- Report on economic theory seminar in Arequipa, Peru, August 1-13 (Reports 001933), 1966; Clague, Christopher K. (Box 74)
  Economics -- Peru -- Congresses
- Consultant's report on establishment of a National Evaluation Program by the Ministry of Education, Government of Chile (Reports 001934), 1966; King, Richard G., 1922- (Box 74)
  A nation-wide testing program for elementary and secondary school students is evaluated.
  Achievement tests -- Chile; Universities and colleges -- Chile -- Admission; Universities and colleges -- Chile -- Entrance examinations; School children -- Chile; Chile. Ministerio de Educación Pública
- Report on educational television in Mexico, January 3 - January 19 (Reports 001935), 1967; Culkin, John M. (Box 74)
- Report of a survey of the libraries of the National Engineering University, Lima, Peru with recommendations (Reports 001936), 1966; Woodward, Rupert C. (Box 74)
  06290324;L66-106
  Library science -- Peru; Library administration -- Peru; Library buildings -- Peru; Academic libraries -- Peru; Universidad Nacional de Ingenieria (Peru)
- Institute for Social and Economic Research: Development in the Eastern Caribbean Islands. Series Four, Manpower Surveys (Reports 001937), 1966; Shurcliff, Alice W.; Wellemeyer, J. F. (John Fletcher), 1913- (Box 75)
  Labor force characteristics and participation and employment forecasts by industry groups are discussed.
  Employment (Economic theory); Industrial organization (Economic theory); Labor supply -- Anguilla; Occupational surveys -- Anguilla; University of the West Indies. Institute for Social and Economic Research (Kingston, Jamaica)
- Visit to Brazil: consultation with regard to the science and technology projects (Reports 001938), 1966; Lauchner, Julian H. (Box 75)
  Title sufficient as abstract. A memo to Stacey Widdicombe.
  Oceanography -- Brazil; Technical institutes -- Brazil; Chemistry -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Brazil; Engineering -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Brazil; Science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Brazil; Universidade Federal do Rio de Janeiro; Universidade Federal de São Paulo; Universidade de Säao Paulo. Oceanographic Institute.
- Field report: trip to Uruguay, Paraguay and Argentina: April 7-17 (Reports 001939), 1966; Parsons, Kenneth H. (Box 75)
  Brief evaluation of agricultural development in the three countries.
  International Division;Latin America and the Caribbean;International Division;Latin America and the Caribbean
  Rural development -- Latin America; Agricultural development projects -- Uruguay; Agricultural development projects -- Paraguay; Agricultural development projects -- Argentina
- Report of trip to the Dominican Republic December 21, 1966-January 5 (Reports 001940), 1967; Lowenthal, Abraham F. (Box 75)
  Brief evaluation of the current educational and political scene in the Dominican Republic.
  Education -- Dominican Republic; Politics, Practical -- Dominican Republic; Committee on Dominican Studies (Dominican Republic)
- Program for the Centro Nacional de Productividad in Management Development and Organization Improvement in Industrial Enterprises (Reports 001941), 1966; Wallace, Emmett (Box 75)
  Industrialization -- Mexico; Industrial management -- Mexico; Executives -- Training of -- Mexico; Labor productivity -- Mexico; Mexican Productivity Center (Mexico)
- Trip report and recommendations on Central America library consultation, October 3-December 21 (Reports 001942), 1966; Andrews, James C. (Box 75)
  Report contains a memo to the Rector of the University of El Salvador. Recommendations are made to improve the caliber of library personnel.
  Librarians -- Central America; Library administration -- Central America; Library education -- Central America; Library buildings -- Central America; Library planning -- Central America; Libraries -- Central America; Universidad de El Salvador; Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Honduras
- Trip report: Bogota, Colombia, December 4-7 (Reports 001943), 1966; Hunter, John M. (John Merlin), 1921- (Box 75)
  The liberal arts program, business administration curriculum, economics curriculum, and the Center for Development Studies of the Facultad de Ciencias Humanas of the National University of Colombia are examined.
  Industrial management -- Study and teaching -- Colombia -- Bogota; Curriculum planning -- Colombia -- Bogota; Economics -- Study and teaching -- Colombia -- Bogota; General studies -- Colombia -- Bogota; Universidad Nacional de Colombia
- Consultant's report (Reports 001944), 1968; Pettit, Joseph M. (Joseph Mayo) (Box 75)
  Current activities in science and engineering in Mexico are discussed.
  06290324;06600039;06700281
  Central Virginia Educational Television Corporation;National Autonomous University of Mexico (UNAM)
  Engineering -- Mexico; Science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Mexico; National Association of Faculties and Schools of Engineering (Mexico); National Institute for Scientific Research.; Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México
- Notes from interviews during trip to Berlin, June 28-July 10, 1963 (Reports 001945), Burkhardt, Frederick, 1912-2007 (Box 75)
  Letter to Shepard Stone, dated Auust 12, 1963.
  Education and Public Policy;Office of the Vice President
  06390003
  3 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Cultural property -- Protection -- Germany
- Impressions that I gathered on my recent trip to Brazil (Reports 001946), 1970; Harberger, Arnold C. (Box 75)
  A letter to William B. Carmichael of the Ford Foundation. Graduate training programs in economics in Brazil are discussed.
  06700093
  United States of Brazil
  5 leaves
  Economics -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Brazil; Economists -- Training of -- Brazil; Brazil. Ministry of Planning and Economic Coordination. Center for Training and Research in Economic Development.; Brazil. Ministry of Planning and Economic Coordination. Institute for Research and Applied Economics.; Instituto de Aposentadoria e Pensões dos Industriários (Brazil)
- Some thoughts on grant making and the grantor-grantee relationship (Reports 001947), 1970; Whiting, Basil J. (Box 75)
  Grant administration and monitoring and the Grantor-grantee relationship are examined.
  Subsidies
- Motivation for and problems in establishing an evaluation mechanism in the state of West Bengal (Reports 001948), 1970; Mosley, Kirk T. (Box 75)
  Evaluation of the Family Planning Program in West Bengal.
  Birth control -- Congresses; Population -- Congresses
- Educational television in Israel (Reports 001949), 1971; Stasheff, Edward; Davis, David M. (David McFarland), 1926-2007; Strauss, Thomas Petry (Box 75)
  Three articles published in "Educational television", May 1971. Various activities of Israel's Instructional Television Center are discussed.
  Television in education -- Israel
- Cable television: The endangered revolution (Reports 001950), 1971; Sucherman, Stuart F. (Box 75)
  Published in the "Columbia Journalism Review," May/June 1971. Ownership patterns, franchises, services and other problems inherent in wide-spread use of cable television are discussed.
  Cable television -- United States; Political participation -- United States
- A proposal for the improvement of teacher education in Northern Nigeria (Reports 001951), 1964; Stiles, Lindley Joseph, 1913- (Box 75)
  Elementary school teachers -- Nigeria; Teachers -- Training of -- Nigeria; Teachers colleges -- Nigeria
- The economics of the drug market: heroin: Appendix D (Reports 001952), 1971; Holahan, John (Box 75)
  Heroin economics including production. Policy options, distribution, and consumption are analyzed.
  07090322
  Drug abuse; Economics; Heroin; Marketing; Narcotics
- Drug education: Appendix E (Reports 001953), 1971; Wald, Patricia M.; Abrams, Annette (Box 75)
  An evaluation of the effectiveness of drug education in the schools with recommendations on how to improve it.
  Drug abuse -- Study and teaching -- United States; Narcotics -- United States
- Report no. 2 on visit to Berlin, June 28 - July 10 (Reports 001954), 1963; Burkhardt, Frederick, 1912-2007 (Box 75)
  The grants given to the Free University of Berlin are evaluated and a scholarship program for Latin Americans to study East Europe and the Soviet Union at the OST-Europa Institut is discussed.
  Latin Americans -- Europe, Eastern; Latin Americans -- Germany -- Berlin (Germany); Freie Universität Berlin. Osteuropa-Institut
- India program letter (Reports 001955), 1954; Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989 (Box 75)
  Evaluation of Ford Foundation efforts in India for the years 1952-1954.
  Ford Foundation program letter for India: report no. 50
  Economic development -- India; Endowments -- India -- Evaluation
- Ford Foundation program letter India: report no. 51 (Reports 001956), 1954; Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989 (Box 75)
  The young farmers' exchange program, homemaking extension and the planning team for the national small industries corporation are discussed.
  Exchange of persons programs -- India; Home economics -- India; Rural extension -- India; Rural youth -- India; Small business -- India; International Farm Youth Exchange; Allahabad Agricultural Institute
- Ford Foundation program letter India: report no. 52, Indian education turns a corner (Reports 001957), 1955; Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989 (Box 75)
  The plans of India's national program of educational reconstruction are evaluated.
  Education, Elementary -- India; Education, Higher -- India; Education, Secondary -- India
- Ford Foundation program letter India: Report no. 114, New housing for India's villages (Reports 001958), 1960; Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989; Eyhéralde F., René (Eyhéralde Frías) (Box 75)
  Problems, efforts, and achievements of India's new housing rural housing are discussed.
  05800359
  Housing -- India; Housing, Rural -- India
- A proposed system of awards for the advancement of outstanding young Indians (Reports 001959), 1964 (Box 75)
  Scholarships -- India; Leadership; Professional education -- India
- Multivariate two sample test with dichotomous and continuous variables. I, Location model (Reports 001960), 1969; Afifi, A. A. (Abdelmonem A.), 1939-; Elashoff, Robert M. (Box 75)
  Title sufficient as abstract. Published in Annals of mathematical statistics, v. 40, 1969, pp. 290-298.
  Behavioral sciences;Office of the Vice President
  05700384
  Psychology -- Research; Examinations -- Design and construction; Examinations; Harvard University
- A bibliography of substantive writings on India and Nepal (Reports 001961), 1967; Hill, Rey M. (Box 75)
  [iv], 64 p. -- 27 cm.
  Central planning -- India -- Bibliography; Central planning -- Nepal -- Bibliography; Social planning -- India -- Bibliography; Social planning -- Nepal -- Bibliography; Economic development -- India -- Bibliography; Economic development -- Nepal -- Bibliography
- A bibliography of substantive writings on India and Nepal (Reports 001962), 1969 (Box 75)
  The record of 17 years experience in India and Nepal as represented in the writings of the Ford Foundation staff and advisors. --T.p.
  [iv], 89 p. -- 28 cm.
- Bibliography of substantive writings on India and Nepal (Reports 001963), 1970; Worrall, Robert P. (Box 75)
  " ... comprehensive, although incomplete, record of the writings of Ford Foundation staff and advisors during 19 years in India and Nepal." -- T.p.
  [iv], 35 p. -- 28 cm.
- The Ford Foundation Urban and Regional Development Advisory Program in Chile (Reports 001964), 1966; Friedmann, John (Box 75)
  Planning -- Chile; Community development -- Chile; Regional planning -- Chile; Rural development -- Chile; Urbanization -- Chile; City planning -- Chile; Cities and towns -- Research -- Chile; Cities and towns -- Study and teaching -- Chile
- Liquidity study of the Foundation's portfolio holdings: information paper: Investment Research Staff (Reports 001965), 1974 (Box 75)
  Investments -- United States; Business cycles -- United States
- Evaluation of the library situation at the Universidad Nacional del Sur (Reports 001966), 1969; Bixler, Paul Howard, 1899- (Box 75)
  Academic libraries -- Argentina; Universidad Nacional del Sur
- The Ford Foundation and economics in Peru (Reports 001967), 1970; Dye, Richard W. (Box 75)
  Review of the Ford Foundation programs in economics in Peru.
  Economics -- Peru; Economics -- Research -- Peru; Economics -- Study and teaching -- Peru
- Review of economics programs in Peru (Reports 001968), 1970; Ballantyne, Janet Campbell, 1939- (Box 75)
  Comprehensive review of existing economics programs in Peru.
- Program review and forward look for Colombia and Venezuela (Reports 001969), 1970; Cotter, William Ross, 1926-1981 (Box 75)
  Views on current programs and possible future activities.
  Agriculture -- Colombia -- Economic aspects; Agriculture -- Venezuela -- Economic aspects; Birth control -- Colombia; Birth control -- Venezuela; Management -- Colombia; Management -- Venezuela; Economics -- Colombia; Economics -- Venezuela; Law -- Study and teaching; Colombian Agricultural and Livestock Institute; Centro Internacional de Agricultura Tropical; Colombian Association of Faculties of Medicine.; Pan-American Fed. of Association of Med. Faculties.; Center for Developmental Research.
- The Ford Foundation in India and Pakistan, 1952-1970, Oct. 8 (Reports 001970), 1971; Martin, Ian, 1946- (Box 75)
  An analysis of the Ford Foundation's international division objectives, policies and programs.
  L71-311
  [Evaluation and assessment source materials]
  Educational evaluation -- India; Educational evaluation -- Pakistan; Evaluation research (Social action programs) -- India; Evaluation research (Social action programs) -- Pakistan; Pakistan Institute of Development Economics
- Thoughts on educational strategy for rural development in Bangladesh (Reports 001971), 1973; Ahmed, Manzoor, 1940-; Coombs, Philip H. (Philip Hall), 1915-2006 (Box 76)
  Report of a study mission sponsored by the Ford Foundation at the request of the Government of Bangladesh.
  Education -- Bangladesh; Rural development -- Bangladesh
- Notes on social science in Brazil (Reports 001972), 1971; Bonilla, Frank (Box 76)
  Social sciences -- Brazil; Social sciences -- Study and teaching -- Brazil
- Management education in India: a study of international collaboration in institution building (Reports 001973), 1971; Hill, Thomas M. (Thomas Mason); Haynes, W. Warren; Baumgartel, Howard, 1920- (Box 76)
  Title sufficient as abstract. Includes report by: George W. Robbins, "Recommendations for an All-India Institute of Management." Date: Dec. 1959.
  07200223
  Indian Institute Of Management, Ahmedabad, Society
  465 p.
  Industrial management -- Study and teaching -- India; Cost effectiveness -- India; Harvard University. Graduate School of Business Administration; Sloan School of Management; Indian Institute of Management, Ahmedabad; Indian Institute of Management, Calcutta
- A program of energy policy studies (Reports 001974), 1971 (Box 76)
  Power resources -- United States; Environmental protection -- United States; Energy policy -- United States -- History
- Opening up opportunities in public education (Reports 001975), 1971 (Box 76, Reel R-9302)
  The Public Education Program: FY 1971-FY 1977. Prepared for the Education Committee of the Board of Trustees.
  Curriculum planning -- United States; Leadership -- Study and teaching -- United States; Art -- Study and teaching -- United States; School integration -- United States; Television in education -- United States; Teachers -- Training of -- United States; Education
- The Foundation's work on population: information paper, Sept. (Reports 001976), 1970 (Box 76, Reel R-9302)
  An assessment of Foundation population programs in less developed countries.
  Birth control -- Developing countries; Human reproduction -- Developing countries -- Research
- Audiovisual reporting of Foundation supported activity (Reports 001977), 1973 (Box 76)
  Report of a survey conducted by the Office of Public Broadcasting and the Office of Reports to survey the needs and opportunities for the use of audiovisual media in reporting the results of activities supported by the Foundation.
  Office of Reports;Public Broadcasting;Office of the Vice President; National Affairs program
  07390011
  Audio-visual materials
- This idea had to be sound to survive: Assessment of a grant to the University of Illinois for support of the Natural Resources Information System, Nov. (Reports 001978), 1972; Tufo, Peter; Sinton, David.; Steinitz, Carl (Box 76)
  Project evaluation - Division of National Affairs - Ford Foundation. Assessment of a grant to the University of Illinois for support of the Natural Resource Information System (NARIS)--a user-oriented data bank for the eight counties in the northeastern p
  07000428
  The Board Of Trustees Of The University Of Illinois
  Natural resources -- United States; Environmental protection -- United States; Land use -- United States; Conservation of natural resources -- United States; Planning -- United States; National Resources Information Systems Project
- $6 million endowment grant: Children's Television Workshop (Reports 001979), 1972 (Box 76)
  Discusses rationale for funding the Children's Television Workshop.
  Six million dollar endowment grant
  Television in education -- United States -- History; Public television -- United States; Children's Television Workshop
- Public broadcasting and communications (Reports 001980), 1971 (Box 76)
  Examines the Ford Foundation's role in public television. The History of the Ford Foundation's role in the development of public broadcasting is attached as an appendix.
  Public television -- United States -- History; Broadcasting policy -- United States -- History; Mass media -- Social aspects
- Institutional aspects of development in the Middle East (Reports 001981-001), 1972; Berger, Morroe (Box 76)
  This paper was originally presented at the Ford Foundation Review Conference on the Middle East and North Africa held in New York on June 20 - 21, 1972. This paper is also included in the information paper entitled, The Ford Foundation in the Middle East
  PAPER Conference (1972 June 20-21: New York, N.Y.)
  Politics and culture -- Arab countries -- History; Economic assistance -- Political aspects -- Arab countries; Social institutions -- Arab countries -- History; Education -- Arab countries -- History
- Thoughts on the political environment in the Middle East and North Africa (Reports 001981-002), 1972; Hourani, Albert (Box 76)
  Politics and culture -- Arab countries -- History; Education -- Arab countries; Economic development -- Political aspects -- Arab countries
- Development problems in the Arab world (Reports 001981-003), 1972; Stephens, Robert, 1931-1995 (Box 76)
  Politics and culture -- Arab countries -- History; Economic development -- Social aspects -- Arab countries -- History; Social institutions -- Arab countries
- The Ford Foundation in the Middle East: objectives and strategies (Reports 001981-004), 1973 (Box 76)
  Economic development -- Middle East; Politics and culture -- Middle East -- History; Social institutions -- Middle East
- Principles underlying the Foundation's program in North Africa (Reports 001981-005), 1972 (Box 76)
  Politics and culture -- Africa, North; Economic development -- Africa, North; Social institutions -- Africa, North; Education -- Africa, North
- The Ford Foundation in the Middle East and North Africa (Reports 001981-006), 1973; Stephens, Robert, 1931-1995; Hourani, Albert; Berger, Morroe (Box 76)
  "This paper is the second to be produced in the course of a substantial review undertaken by the office for the Middle East and Africa (MEA) of the International Division. The first, entitled "The Ford Foundation and Sub-Sahara Africa," was presented to t
  Economic development -- Arab countries; Politics and culture -- Arab countries; Social institutions -- Arab countries
- Environmental policy studies: a Foundation strategy (Reports 001982), 1973 (Box 76)
  Outlining alternatives and a Foundation strategy for dealing with resources and environmental policy studies in the next five years.
  Environmentalism -- United States; Natural resources -- United States; Ecology -- Research -- United States; Environmental policy -- United States; Resources for the Future; Council on Environmental Quality
- Health and nutrition in India: recommendations for Ford Foundation support (Reports 001983), 1974; Gwatkin, Davidson R. (Box 77)
  Asia and the Pacific;India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  Nutrition -- India; Infants -- India -- Mortality; Child care -- India; Health education -- India; Medical care -- India; Sanitation -- India; Poverty -- India; Agriculture -- India -- Economic aspects
- Affirmative action program for the employment of Women and minorities on the professional staff of the Ford Foundation: a review and analysis (Reports 001984), 1974 (Box 77)
  52 p. -- 28 cm.
  [Affirmative action at Ford Foundation]